[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 18]
Qingyuan!
Don't ruin your entire family
just for your mother!
This has...
never been my family.
Qingyuan!
[Harmony Among Kin]
Since Zhenglun
[A Legacy of Virtue for Eternity]
was registered under my name,
he's the legitimate eldest son of the Xie family.
He deserves
a respectable funeral.
I've invited the Taoist priest from Qingyang Temple
to conduct rites for 7 days.
Please rest assured, Mother.
Wenzhuo.
Yes, Mother.
See to it that
Yinghua's properly taken care of.
When the funeral takes place,
it's only natural and right for the biological mother
to see her son off one last time.
Mother,
the physician said
psychosis is most easily triggered by funerals.
If she makes a scene in the mourning hall,
it'll be a nightmare to handle.
You're truly born stupid.
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
A son of the Xie family
fell on the battlefield,
bringing supreme glory to our name.
If outsiders find out that you, the Head Madam,
prevented his birth mother, a concubine,
from attending
the funeral of her son who died with military distinction,
it's not just you who will be disgraced.
If you're worried,
assign four matrons to watch her.
When the time comes, she can pay her respects
in the side hall.
Yes.
[A Legacy of Virtue for Eternity]
For now, other than Zhenglun's funeral,
leave everything else
in this house alone.
[Harmony Among Kin]
It's been 20 years.
I poured my heart and soul into this family.
But even with Mei Yinghua out of the picture,
she still treats me like this.
[A Legacy of Virtue for Eternity]
Madam,
don't worry.
At best, the Old Madam is weaponizing
her seniority and demands for filial piety against you.
We're not without a backer.
You have your brother.
Why be afraid of her?
I can only rely on him now.
[Cultivate Personal Virtue and Integrity]
My Lady,
I've bought the dried persimmons you asked for.
A portion's been sent to the mourning hall for Eldest Young Master.
I brought the other portion to you.
By the way,
here's a letter from Lord Yan.
[Respectfully to Fourth Lady Qingyuan]
Did Lord Yan
apologize to you?
There was no argument to begin with.
Why'd he apologize?
He's asking me to go see Granny Chen.
I bet he wants her to put in a good word for him.
He's just counting on the fact
that you can't be angry with him in front of Granny.
[Sincerely, Yan Rui]
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Granny is ill.
Lord Yan found out you were sick
before I did.
He's here too, to take care of you.
Here.
Thank you.
Granny,
I've been a bad granddaughter.
Don't say that.
I just caught a mild cold,
and I'm almost all better already.
I'm thrilled that
you and Yan are here.
But my baby,
running out so late at night,
are you sure it's okay?
It's fine.
The entire Xie family is in a mess
and busy with the funeral.
No one has time to mind me.
I heard about that too.
They all say Eldest Young Master Xie
was an upright man.
What a pity.
Dear,
don't be too sad.
Eldest Young Master Xie
led a noble and virtuous life.
He's destined for a blessed next life.
He'll be born into a wealthy and kind family.
I'll go boil the medicine for you.
Then I'll recover even faster.
Yan.
Come here.
Come here!
Granny.
Yan,
Yunya has always
kept things to herself since she was little.
It seems
Eldest Young Master Xie's death has been
quite a big blow to her.
Please help me comfort her.
Rest assured.
These are freshly dried persimmons from Northern Frontier.
They're soft and sweet.
I picked three kinds
and chose the sweetest one for you.
Take a look.
If you like them,
I'll dry a whole rack when I get back
just for us siblings to eat.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Even Granny Chen could tell you're troubled.
She asked me to comfort you.
When my eldest brother
came back this time,
he brought me some Northern Frontier dried persimmons.
I liked them very much.
He said he'd bring me more next time.
But there won't be a next time.
Sometimes I wonder:
if I hadn't
come to the Xie Residence,
would he still be alive?
Yan Rui,
why are human lives
so short?
So short that there's...
not even time for a proper goodbye.
Xie Qingyuan,
it's not your fault.
That was a battlefield,
where thousands of lives are sacrificed for one general's victory.
As a general,
Zhenglun must've been prepared for this.
Many soldiers perish in battle.
Zhenglun isn't the first,
and he won't be the last.
I've seen arrows fall like rainstorms
and wounded comrades crawling in the mud.
The blood soaked in melted snow...
is as hot as this stove.
I've actually been wanting to ask you...
Are you...
-Actually, I… -Yan.
It's time to go.
It's 7:45 PM.
You're leaving?
Hengtang is full of watchful eyes.
If we don't leave now,
who knows what trouble might come.
Wait for me to come back.
When I come back,
whatever you want to know...
I will tell you.
I told you
she'd only hold you back.
[Chen]
So,
you came to find me an hour early?
I'm cutting the Gordian knot.
You were reluctant to leave,
so I had to give you a push.
Let Granny have a look at you.
You've lost weight.
Blame the chefs at Xie Residence.
Their cooking isn't as good as yours.
When did you learn to be a smooth talker?
Sit here.
I'll make you 2 sugar pancakes,
your favorite when you were a kid.
Granny,
you just took your medicine. Go to sleep.
I'm okay.
Feel my forehead.
After taking your medicine, my fever is gone.
You don't want food,
but I do! How else am I
to fall asleep?
Eat some with me.
Okay.
I'll make it.
Will it taste the same if you make it?
Sit here and wait.
Yan is such a good kid.
When I come back,
whatever you want to know,
I will tell you.
Granny?
Granny.
Lady Xie.
Lord Wei, what brings you here
at this late hour?
I came to ask you for a cup of tea, of course.
Sorry to trouble you.
I only have low-grade tea,
which might not suit your taste.
Therefore,
I must trouble you
to come with me.
Yunya, run!
Granny!
Let her go!
I'll go with you.
My Lord!
Stop the carriage.
Fourth Lady's been abducted.
I was also told to relay a message:
go to the old Shen residence
alone,
or she dies!
If you go,
we're no longer brothers.
Lord Wei,
if you're trying to use me as bait
to lure Lord Yan out,
I'm afraid you'll be disappointed.
I'm just a plaything for Lord Yan
in Hengtang
to kill time
when he is bored.
If you don't believe me,
you can lock me up for a night and see.
Ouch, My Lady,
your words are like daggers to my heart.
Lord Yan, how gutsy of you
to come alone.
Impressive.
Lord Wei,
you went to such lengths to lure me here,
but have you ever considered
that if you kill me,
you won't live either?
Then let's find out.
Even if I can't defeat you,
someone will accompany me to the afterlife.
Lord Yan,
doesn't this place
feel familiar to you?
My Lord,
guilty of bribery and corruption,
Shen Zhibai's estate has been seized,
and 73 people in his residence
have been executed on the spot.
But...
What is it?
His eldest son, Shen Run,
wasn't among them.
Someone saw him in a house in the south of the city.
Leave no survivors.
Go find him now!
Yes!
That night, 9 years ago,
the whole family here was killed overnight,
and only two kids managed to escape.
Before, I couldn't figure out
why you,
Lord Yan, targeted me at every turn.
But the night of the grain distribution,
I finally understood.
The enemy is right in front of you,
yet you still think about that woman.
Do you really think you're Yan Rui?
You're one of the two bastards who escaped from the Shen residence—
Shen Run.
Kill him.
Freeze!
Wei Changyan,
I can give you a way out.
Let her go, and I'll
personally escort you out of the city.
Such great kindness, Lord Yan.
You're making me emotional.
However,
you must also show some sincerity.
Forget about me.
If I die,
kill him for me.
What a woman of steel.
Lord Yan,
if you don't want her dead,
put down the sword.
Kill him!
♪ I counted every moment ♪
♪ Memories take root; the annual rings grow ♪
♪ Who bore the parting wind ♪
♪ And wove it gently into the warmth of the past? ♪
Have you ever loved a woman?
♪ I honor every scar upon your hand ♪
I just want to know
♪ Through endless nights, a lone soul wanders this mortal world ♪
under what circumstances
a man would
♪ Turning back, we embrace— one fleeting moment of love and hate ♪
give up the woman he loves.
♪ As flowers fall beneath the dusk ♪
Don't be anxious.
I'll send you two star-crossed lovers to the afterlife
together right now.
To protect her.
Yan...
All we can do is
remember the faces of our enemies.
When we grow up,
no matter where they hide,
no matter how many of them there are,
we must bring the truth to light
and bring the sinners to justice.
[Qinyue Corridor]
Go inside.
Clean yourself up.
Don't get caught.
But I still have a lot of things to do—
I know.
Meet me at midnight,
[Danyue Pavilion]
at the place we said goodbye back then.
I'll tell you everything.
I'll wait for you.
Go along.
[Danyue Pavilion]
My Lady!
You're finally back!
Why are you covered in blood?
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
I'm great.
How could you be fine?
I'll get you some clean clothes.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Sesame flatbread!
Fresh out of the oven!
♪ Spring comes to the long gate, green grass sprouts ♪
♪ Red plums bear dewdrops, bright and serene ♪
♪ Year by year, time drifts along ♪
Never have I imagined
that the hours from dawn to dusk
♪ Warmth and chill of mortal meet and part ♪
could be so painfully long.
♪ No need to heed the wind's soft whisper and ask about your return ♪
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds, waiting for the moon to rest ♪
Shen Run, I miss you so much.
I have
so much to say to you after all this time.
♪ Old memories lie heavy, haunting every dream ♪
I've also dreamed up
countless ways we would reunite
or
♪ Rises and falls take turns ♪
tragically miss each other for a lifetime.
♪ Phases of the moon, unplanned to wax and wane ♪
I just never imagined
♪ Count fallen blooms, yet never count all pains of parting ♪
that fate had already
woven us together,
long before
we even knew it.
♪ You, tender yet sharp, with thorns by your side ♪
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
Baoxian.
My Lady!
What time is it?
It'll be dark in half an hour.
♪ The wind and rain sigh, the road stretches far ♪
♪ Blossoms drift with streams, affections softly stir ♪
[Danyue Pavilion]
♪ Half real, half illusion; one cup of spring awakes me ♪
My Lady!
Where are you going?
[Danyue Pavilion]
If I'd known it was you earlier,
♪ Burned and released, held by fate's hand ♪
would things be
different between us now?
Perhaps I should accept
that meeting like this
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze and homebound sail to land ♪
is the best arrangement heaven has for us.
♪ Slim moonbeams weave tangled dreams all night ♪
♪ The homeward boat glides slowly through dark twilight ♪
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring fades to lingering cheer ♪
Shen Run!
Yunya, I'm sorry.
I broke my promise again.
Many times, I wanted to let you know who I am.
But when I thought about
how we both have our own revenge to seek
and our uncertain endings,
I asked myself what the best outcome
for our relationship would be.
It'd be to maintain our own paths
without disturbing each other's hearts.
But how could my heart
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds, waiting for the moon to rest ♪
possibly resist you?
You know what, Yunya?
♪ Old memories lie heavy, haunting every dream ♪
I thought there was nothing left
for me in this world
but revenge.
♪ Rises and falls take turns ♪
Until I met you.
♪ Phases of the moon, unplanned to wax and wane ♪
The little girl who
gave me hope on that snowy night
♪ Count fallen blooms, yet never count all pains of parting ♪
has now grown up.
She is prettier
and braver.
♪ You, tender yet sharp, with thorns by your side ♪
Little Monkey,
I've never forgotten our oath.
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
Please wait for me.
I shall return
to fulfill our tryst
at the ruined temple.
♪ The wind and rain sigh, the road stretches far ♪
♪ Blossoms drift with streams, affections softly stir ♪
♪ Half real, half illusion; one cup of spring awakes me ♪
♪ Burned and released, held by fate's hand ♪
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze and homebound sail to land ♪
♪ Slim moonbeams weave tangled dreams all night ♪
♪ The homeward boat glides slowly through dark twilight ♪
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring fades to lingering cheer ♪
♪ I chant and sigh; one cup of spring, drunk through turns of year ♪
I'm so sorry about Zhenglun.
You and Old Madam must be heartbroken right now.
But today is your birthday after all.
Let's have a chat
to ease your mind.
Why don't I see Qingrong?
That child's been
acting strangely these past few days.
She always looks listless,
as if something is weighing on her mind.
The girl is growing up
and has her own ideas.
She'll be fine in a few days.
Here, have some tea.
What are you doing here?
Aren't you keen on that phony?
What?
Your lover packed up and left,
so you want to seduce my Chunzhi again?
I'm asking you a question.
Qingru.
Mother, your hairpin
looks simple
and elegant,
but it doesn't look ordinary.
You're too young to know.
This hairpin was
made by a master craftsman in Jiangnan.
It's truly
one of a kind.
It's just an old thing.
It's inappropriate to wear flashy things during the mourning period,
so I made it a point to pick a simple one.
I shot it right in the head,
killing it instantly
with just one arrow.
I'll show you.
Look at my archery skills.
Aren't I cool?
Do you know her?
Long time no see.
Chunzhi.
Qingru's been
studying floral art since she was little.
Her use of peonies today
is just wonderful.
What do you think?
Good.
Very good.
Chunzhi,
you two hang out here.
I'll go prepare some fruit.
Thank you, Mother.
Good girl.
Take care, Madam Hu.
Marriages in a small place like Hengtang
have always been like this.
They look for families of equal status
and choose those with similar backgrounds.
In the end,
it's just picking from the leftovers of these
four or five families.
Even if both families detest each other,
well aware that
the other is far from virtuous,
they still go through with the marriage alliance.
All they want is for their descendants
to be deeply rooted
in Hengtang,
so as to
safeguard their place at this table of future wealth.
These words of yours
are truly
enlightening.
For this marriage between
the Xie family and the marquis's,
no matter who is chosen in the end,
it's a great blessing
for the Xie family.
Everyone says you're clever.
Meeting you today,
I see it is indeed true.
It seems you've already anticipated it.
I understand.
Young Master Li thinks he is engaged to me,
when you and my mother have actually chosen
my second sister.
Next,
which of these two do you want to use?
Either is fine.
Pick one. Look.
Which color?
This one then.
Since you've seen through it,
I'll be frank with you.
Chunzhi always told me
you're the only one he'll marry.
I have reasoned with him many times,
but he takes after his father.
Once he sets his mind on something,
no one can persuade him otherwise.
I do have doubts about your background,
but what I'm more concerned about
is that marrying someone who doesn't love you
dooms you to a lifetime of misery and heartbreak.
I can't let that happen to my boy.
I understand.
That's why
I'm willing to
play along with the plan you and Mother set up today.
What a pity.
Here you are.
Mother.
Try these freshly picked fruits.
This is nice.
Qingru!
Come here.
Chunzhi,
wait for me here.
This has always been Chunzhi's favorite fruit.
Bring them to him
and keep him company.
Yes.
Qingyuan.
Come,
let me.
Mother,
Madam Li.
all of Hengtang is talking about
Chunzhi and Qingyuan's marriage.
Why are you still letting them spend time together?
Madam Li,
it's time
we have a good talk about
Chunzhi and Qingru's marriage.
Qingyuan,
This "Time-Tested Formulas for Lifelong Wellness"
is from my family's collection.
This is likely the world's only copy
outside the imperial archives.
I thought you might find it useful.
[Time-Tested Formulas for Lifelong Wellness]
This is too precious.
I've done nothing to earn it.
Just take it.
My family knows nothing about medicine.
It'll just gather dust in our study.
You, on the other hand,
might be able to use it to save lives in the future.
[Time-Tested Formulas for Lifelong Wellness]
You know how I feel,
and I know what you think.
Aren't we a kind of perfect match?
People always say
humans are cold and fickle.
One minute you like something,
and the next you don't.
But I believe
the opposite is also true:
one can grow to love someone
they used to have
no feelings for.
Qingyuan,
I'm serious about marrying you.
What if one day you actually
start falling for me?
What if?
If I were fickle,
how could I be worthy
of your affection?
Qingyuan.
Don't jump to conclusions just yet.
I believe
that someday,
you'll give me an answer.
Chunzhi.
Come here.
Okay!
Qingyuan,
my mother needs me.
I'll be right back.
My Lady,
Marchioness of Danyang has made it clear
that she disagrees with this marriage.
Why didn't you...
Young Master Li
is too pure-hearted to
anticipate such schemes.
Since I'm not planning to marry him,
there's no need to go into all that.
And I don't want to be
the villain who drives a wedge between mother and son.
But Madam Hu is quite strange too.
She actually let you
and her carefully chosen son-in-law
admire flowers together.
Qingrong.
You've been so preoccupied lately.
What is going on?
Talk to me.
Please put my mind at ease.
Mother,
was my birth mother
really killed by Mei Yinghua?
I resented Jin Chunqing for so many years.
Did I get it all wrong?
Mother,
is there more
to my mother's death?
Oh, Mei Yinghua,
after all the evil you've done...
Everyone knows
she's just trying to wiggle out of trouble.
How could you believe her words?
I...
Since you were little,
you've always been too straightforward
and easily misled.
I've protected you for 19 years,
but I can't
protect you forever.
If you believe everything
others say
or do,
my heart will
break with worry.
Mother,
I...
Qingrong,
you've always been
smarter than Qingru and Qinghe.
No matter what others say,
you should know in your heart
who
truly cares about you.
If
you feel restless,
go to the ancestral hall
and burn some Rebirth Sutras for your mother.
It's a way to pray for her peace in the afterlife.
Rest early then,
Mother.